A Guide to the Arena Stage Collection: Production Contracts 1987-1999
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Arena Stage Collection: Production Contracts 1987-1999
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University Libraries
Arena 0014
4 boxes, 1 1/3 cubic feet (2.25 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Arena Stage in the fall of 2000
Historical Information
Arena Stage was an early leader in the resident theater movement. One of the first not-for-profit theaters in the United States as well as a pioneer of the regional theater movement the Arena Stage was the first regional theater to transfer a production to Broadway, the first invited by the U.S. State Department to tour behind the Iron Curtain and the first to receive a Tony Award. Co-founded in 1950 by Edward Mangum a teacher from the George Washington University, and Zelda Fichandler one of his students, Arena Stage was opened in Washington D.C. to fill the void left by the closing of the National Theater in 1948. Deriving it's name from the idea of "theater in the round," Arena Stage became one of the first resident theaters in the United States, beginning with a company of only eight actors. Today, Arena performs to over 250,000 patrons during a September to June season and employs nearly 200 theater professionals and craft persons, who are responsible for all the costumes and scenery seen on stage. Many now- famous actors took part in Arena Stage productions during the early part of their careers. Some of them include Robert Prosky, Morgan Freeman, Dianne Weist, James Earl Jones, Kevin Kline, Christopher Guest, Yeardly Smith and Samuel L. Jackson. Donated to George Mason University in fall of 2000, the Arena Stage Collection contains materials spanning the theater's 50 year history including production notebooks, photographs, playbills, scrapbooks, scripts and handwritten correspondence and other production materials.
Scope and Content
Series contains contracts and related information for selected productions of Arena Stage. Years covered are 1987-1999.
Arrangement
By production title
Contents List
- Arena Stage Collection: Production Contracts
  - Crime and Punishment 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - Yuri Lyubimov (Box Box 1)
  - The Piggy Bank 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - Measure for Measure (Box Box 1)
  - The Marriage of Bette and Boo 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - Flying Karamazov Brothers 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - Beehive 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - Challenge Grant 90-94 (Box Box 1)
  - Endowment Camp 85/86 (Box Box 1)
  - Capital Needs List (Box Box 1)
  - Ourselves Alone 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - Glengarry Glen Ross (Box Box 1)
  - All the King's Men 87/88 (Box Box 1)
  - Joe Turner's Come and Gone 87/88 (Box Box 1)
  - The Immigrant 1987 (Box Box 1)
  - NEA / Richard Willbur tribute 3/88 (Box Box 1)
  - Light up the Sky 87/88 (Box Box 1)
  - American Splendor (stage four) 87/88 (Box Box 1)
  - Zeisler Award 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - American Theatre Season, The Crucible 87/88 (Box Box 1)
  - The Crucible 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - American Theater Season (Box Box 1)
  - Late Great Ladies of Blues and Jazz, '87 (Box Box 1)
  - Creative Programs/Dennis Doran 1/87 - 4/87 (Box Box 1)
  - Heartbreak House 86/87 (Box Box 1)
  - The Asti Sponsored Soviet Designer visit 5/88 (Box Box 2)
  - Arena Tour 1986-1987 (Israel) (Box Box 2)
  - NEA playwright in Residence 1986-1987 (Box Box 2)
  - Gang of Five 85/86 (Box Box 2)
  - Enrico IV 87/88 (Box Box 2)
  - Les Blancs 87/88 (Box Box 2)
  - Checkmate (stage four) 87/88 (Box Box 2)
  - Janice F. Hill (Box Box 2)
  - The Cherry Orchard 87/88 (Box Box 2)
  - Bill Stewart Stamp Award (Box Box 2)
  - A Chorus of Disapproval 1/89 (Box Box 2)
  - Briar Patch (Box Box 2)
  - Playboy of the West Indies (Box Box 2)
  - 6 Characters in Search of an Author (Box Box 2)
  - Ring Around the Moon (Box Box 2)
  - An Acting Workshop (Box Box 2)
  - Abyssinia (Box Box 2)
  - Suzaki / Lear (Box Box 2)
  - Coconuts (Box Box 2)
  - Judevine (stage 4), May 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - On The Town, April 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - Nothing Sacred, March 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - Lie of the Mind, March 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - The Fool Show (Geoff Hoyle) Feb. 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - Senior Staff meeting minutes, 1997-1998 (Box Box 3)
  - Senior Staff meeting minutes, 1996-1997 (Box Box 3)
  - 1995-1996 senior staff meeting minutes (Box Box 3)
  - A Walk in the Woods, symposium June, 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - A Walk in the Woods, June 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - Soviet Union tour 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - Merrily We Roll Along, January 1990 (Box Box 3)
  - The Man Who Came to Dinner 11/1989 (Box Box 3)
  - The Glass Menagerie 10/89 (Box Box 3)
  - A Midsummers Night's Dream 9/89 (Box Box 3)
  - Stand-Up Tragedy 1/90 (Box Box 3)
  - Born Guilty, 1989-1990 (Box Box 3)
  - Juno and the Paycock 5/90 (Box Box 3)
  - Fences 4/90 (Box Box 3)
  - Conquest of the SOuth Pole 3/90 (Box Box 3)
  - A Doll House 3/90 (Box Box 3)
  - Closer Than Ever (book-in) 9/90 (Box Box 3)
  - The Seagull 5/91 (Box Box 3)
  - Two Gentlemen of Verona 5/91 (Box Box 3)
  - Vivisections from the Blown Mind 4/91 (Box Box 3)
  - She Stoops to Conquer 3/91 (Box Box 3)
  - My Children, My Africa! 1/91 (Box Box 3)
  - Pygmalion 2/91 (Box Box 3)
  - Born Guilty 1/91 (Box Box 4)
  - From the Mississippi Delta 12/90 (Box Box 4)
  - Our Town 11/90 (Box Box 4)
  - Cerceau 10/90 (Box Box 4)
  - Caucasian Chalk Circle 9/90 (Box Box 4)
  - Grants and Contributions 1982 (Box Box 4)
  - Grants and Contributions 1980-1981 (Box Box 4)
  - Grants 1986 (Box Box 4)
  - Grants and Contributions (Box Box 4)
  - Fine Commission 1991-1992 (Box Box 4)
  - NEH 1991-1992 (Box Box 4)
  - Rockefeller Grant 1991-1992 (Box Box 4)
  - MUS appl. 1990-1993 (Box Box 4)
  - NEA: opera musical theater program 1993-1994 (Box Box 4)
  - Fine Arts Commission 1990-1991 (Box Box 4)
  - DC Commission (Box Box 4)